PRACHI VAVHAL

Location: Nashik,India. Contact Number: +91 9623732027 Email: prachisvavhal@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/prachisv04 Website: prachisv04.github.io

PROFILE SUMMARY

 Aspiring Software engineer with one year and seven months of experience, skilled in backend development using OOPs, Java, SQL, Spring Boot and related technologies.

 My pursuit centres on leading a healthy life, attaining continuous professional advancement, enhancing knowledge base, connecting people and developing new technologies as part of progressive organisation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Health Break February 2023–Present

- Determined to prioritise my well-being, following the accident I took a career hiatus to focus on my health.
- Utilised the time to stay progressive through continuous learning and assisting students with their academics and projects.

Associate Software Developer | Amdocs, Pune August 2021-February 2023

- Contributed to two clients as a crucial member of the scrum team, and collaborated with other teams in a cross-functional setting.
- Engaged in every development phase like analysis, implementation, testing, code review, and release.
- Executed over 20 user stories, contributing to 10%–50% of development in various sprint iterations.
- Enhanced the project code standard through resolution of more than 400 sonar issues.
- Addressed over 15 defects, leading to a 15% reduction in the project's pending issues.
- Proposed solutions and Actively engaged in discussions, resulting in a 60% increase in the personal participation rate.
- Skills: Java, J2EE, JDBC, Spring Boot, RDBMS, SQL, PLSQL, Object-Relational Mapping, Web Services, Perforce, JIRA, Microservices, Unit Testing, Debugging.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java: Object oriented Programming, J2EE, JDBC, Web Services, JSP, Collection API

Databases: SQL, PLSQL, (MySQL, Oracle, MS SQLServer)

Data Structures & algorithms, Design Patterns

Spring Framework, Microservices, Hibernate, SOAP, REST API

Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React.js

Tools: Maven, GIT, Perforce, Jira, Jenkins, Agile (SCRUM).

Unit Testing, Cloud: GCP.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Sentiment Analyzer | December 2020-March 2021 | GitHub

Sentiment analysis module built using **Python** libraries, ReactJS, and MongoDB, based on machine learning techniques.

- Enforced rigorous data cleaning processes and categorization to 10K+ tweets extracted directly from social media.
- Presented sentiment trends using insightful graphs and maps (10 per category).

Project Management System | February 2020-April 2020 | GitHub

An application built using Java, JSP, JDBC, and MYSQL, for students and facilitated scheduling and evaluation, resulting in automation of process by 80%.

 Designed and built Data Access layer, and Controller layer through reusable and maintainable code, affecting 40% of development of the system.

EDUCATION

BE (Bachelor of Engineering) in Information Technology | Pune

Pune Institute of Computer Technology, Pune. (8.38) August 2018–April 2021

Diploma in Computer Technology | Nashik

Government Polytechnic Nashik, Nashik. (89.31%) July 2015–May 2018

VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

"Addiction": College Annual Event | January 2020

Headed the audition team, entitled to conduct auditions of over 200 students by proper communication and time management for all stakeholders.

• "Enthusia": College Technical Event: Coding Event Lead | September 2019

I guided a competitive coding event, where I managed over 100 enrolled participants. Incorporated multitasking capabilities by being part of various units at once.

LANGUAGES

Proficient in English, Hindi, and Marathi.